Clayton Seitz

cwseitz@uchicago.edu cwseitz.github.io

SUMMARY

My research primarily consists of the application high-dimensional stochastic methods, information theory, and Bayesian statistical inference to problems related to digital image processing and unsupervised learning of gene interaction networks. This sometimes involves algorithm development at the level of model inference from data which can require optimization of deep networks and/or graphical models. I am primarily familiar with optimization algorithms inspired by physics e.g., Langevin dynamics, MCMC, and simulated annealing. I am also interested in the implementation of statistical inference in the dynamics of recurrent networks of integrate and fire neurons. This is a Bayesian interpretation of neural dynamics and neural sampling, inspired by the Boltzmann machine.

In my personal life, I like to write music and digital signal processing software for audio effects. Also, I like to tinker with vintage vacuum tube amplifiers and occasionally do some woodworking.

EDUCATION

Master of Science, Biophysics

University of Chicago, Chicago, IL, 2021

Thesis: Towards a theory of stable cell assembly formation in excitatory-inhibitory neuronal networks

Bachelor of Science, Magna Cum Laude, Physics

Purdue University, Indianapolis, IN, 2019

Minor: Mathematics

Bachelor of Science, Magna Cum Laude, Informatics

Luddy School of Informatics, Computing, and Engineering, Indiana University Bloomington, 2019

Concentration: Mathematics

COMPUTER SKILLS

Languages & Software: Python, Tensorflow, C, Git, LaTeX, Bash

EXPERIENCE

Research Technician

2019-2021

Indiana University - Purdue University, Indianapolis, IN

- Develop an image processing software pipeline for high-throughput quantification of images in fluorescence microscopy
- Utilize high performance computing clusters for image segmentation, single particle tracking, and image registration

Undergraduate Researcher

2019-2020

Indiana University - Purdue University, Indianapolis, IN

- Utilize time-correlated single photon counting (TCSPC) to characterize the sub-Poissonian emission of organic quantum dots dispersed in a thin film of poly-methyl methacrylate (PMMA)
- Design and utilize a 3-color imaging protocol to perform single-molecule imaging of mRNA transcripts in human epithelial kidney and osteosarcoma cells

Undergraduate Tutor

2018-2019

2019

Indiana University - Purdue University, Indianapolis, IN

• Tutored undergraduate students in introductory physics courses covering classical mechanics, classical electromagnetism, circuit analysis, and modern physics

AWARDS

PS-ON Annual Investigator Meeting Travel Award Indiana University - Purdue University, Indianapolis, IN

Hudson and Holland Scholarship for Diversity and Inclusion 2013-2017

Indiana University, Bloomington, IN

Founders Scholar 2013-2017

Indiana University, Bloomington, IN

Cigital Scholarship 2016-2017

Indiana University, Bloomington, IN

Dean's List 2013-2019

Indiana University, Bloomington, IN

PUBLICATIONS Wenting Wu, Farooq Syed, Edward Simpson, Chih-Chun Lee, Jing Liu, Garrick Chang, Chuanpeng Dong, Clayton Seitz, Decio L. Eizirik, Raghavendra G. Mirmira, Yunlong Liu, Carmella Evans-Molina; Impact of Proinflammatory Cytokines on Alternative Splicing Patterns in Human Islets. Diabetes 1 January 2022; 71 (1): 116–127

> Mengdi Zhang, Clayton Seitz, Garrick Chang, Fadil Iqbal, Hua Lin, and Jing Liu A guide for single-particle chromatin tracking in live cell nuclei. Cell Biology International (In Review).